=Recruit A General to lead the Troops=
=Ambil Seorang Jeneral untuk mengetuai Pasukan=
=Episode 21=
=Episod 21=
Li Aotian!
Li Aotian!
Perfect timing, Chengyu.
Masa yang tepat, Chengyu.
News from the capital. The Chancellor has taken his own life.
Berita dari ibu negara. Canselor telah mengambil nyawanya sendiri.
What?
apa?
We need to figure out
Kita perlu memikirkan
something.
sesuatu.
Got it.
faham.
Where are you going?
awak nak pergi mana?
None of your business.
Bukan urusan anda.
Are you going to find Chen Xinrou?
Adakah anda akan mencari Chen Xinrou?
Don't you get it?
Adakah anda tidak faham?
Now that things have come to this point, she doesn't matter anymore.
Sekarang keadaan sudah sampai ke tahap ini, dia tidak peduli lagi.
She does.
Dia lakukan.
She matters more than anyone else.
Dia lebih penting daripada orang lain.
Xinrou!
Xinrou!
If you're gone...
Jika awak sudah tiada...
Chengyu.
Chengyu.
It's too late.
dah terlambat.
Chen Xinrou is dead.
Chen Xinrou sudah mati.
So are the Chancellor
Begitu juga dengan Canselor
and his followers.
dan pengikutnya.
If we join forces,
Jika kita bersatu tenaga,
no one can match us.
tiada siapa yang dapat menandingi kita.
Chengyu.
Chengyu.
I'm your brother.
Saya abang awak.
Let's stage a rebellion together.
Mari kita lakukan pemberontakan bersama-sama.
Then this world will belong to our family!
Maka dunia ini akan menjadi milik keluarga kita!
I don't care to whom this world belong. I don't want it!
Saya tidak kisah dunia ini milik siapa. Saya tidak mahu!
Yet if anything happens to Xinrou,
Namun jika apa-apa berlaku kepada Xinrou,
I'll make you pay with your life.
Saya akan membuat anda membayar dengan nyawa anda.
Well done.
Syabas.
Chen Xinrou is gone for good.
Chen Xinrou telah pergi untuk selamanya.
Since you like me,
Memandangkan awak suka saya,
you must remember
anda mesti ingat
to always back me up.
untuk sentiasa menyokong saya.
(Qingfeng Stronghold)
(Kubu kuat Qingfeng)
(Chen Xinrou is dead.)
(Chen Xinrou sudah mati.)
(Qingfeng Stronghold is having a grand funeral,)
(Kubu Kuat Qingfeng sedang mengadakan pengebumian besar-besaran,)
(and no outsiders are allowed.)
(dan orang luar tidak dibenarkan.)
(But you can access it.)
(Tetapi anda boleh mengaksesnya.)
I've betrayed them.
Saya telah mengkhianati mereka.
Since you've chosen this path,
Memandangkan anda telah memilih jalan ini,
don't ever try to be considerate of them.
jangan sesekali cuba bertimbang rasa terhadap mereka.
Do me this one last favor.
Berikan saya bantuan terakhir ini.
Once the task is dealt with,
Setelah tugas itu diuruskan,
I'll marry you.
Saya akan berkahwin dengan awak.
(Help me get rid of)
(Bantu saya hilangkan)
(Li Chengyu.)
(Li Chengyu.)
I knew it were you.
Saya tahu itu awak.
I'm sorry.
saya minta maaf.
I was left with no choice.
Saya ditinggalkan tanpa pilihan.
And I'm done with making choices.
Dan saya sudah selesai membuat pilihan.
Did you know that Tao Lianxin
Adakah anda tahu bahawa Tao Lianxin
gave Xinrou a life-saving hairpin when she was in jail?
memberi Xinrou sepit rambut yang menyelamatkan nyawa semasa dia di penjara?
Put it on.
Pakai.
Did you know she could've stabbed you
Adakah anda tahu dia boleh menikam anda
(when you were poisoning her?)
(semasa anda meracuninya?)
Did you know she'd rather suffer to death
Tahukah anda dia lebih suka menderita sampai mati
(than killing you with that hairpin?)
(daripada membunuh awak dengan jepit rambut itu?)
She trusted you
Dia percayakan awak
and treated you so well.
dan melayan kamu dengan baik.
Yet you did that to her.
Tapi awak buat macam tu pada dia.
She will not rest in peace.
Dia tidak akan berehat dengan tenang.
Guards.
Pengawal.
Get them out of here.
Bawa mereka keluar dari sini.
It was you.
Ia adalah awak.
How come it was you?
Kenapa awak?
Li Chengyu.
Li Chengyu.
Li Chengyu!
Li Chengyu!
It turned out it was you.
Ternyata itu adalah awak.
I'm sorry.
saya minta maaf.
Li Chengyu!
Li Chengyu!
That useless Qin Manyue,
Qin Manyue yang tidak berguna itu,
what's taking her so long?
apa yang menyebabkan dia begitu lama?
She's failed it for sure.
Dia pasti gagal.
Chengyu.
Chengyu.
Since you're not going to join my side,
Memandangkan awak tidak akan menyertai saya,
that makes us enemies.
yang menjadikan kita musuh.
Instead of fighting a war,
Daripada berperang,
I should just get rid of you now.
Saya hanya perlu menyingkirkan anda sekarang.
Hang in there, Xinrou.
Tunggu di sana, Xinrou.
We're on the way to the medical hall,
Kami dalam perjalanan ke dewan perubatan,
so hang in there.
jadi tahan di sana.
We're almost there.
Kita hampir sampai.
Let's go home.
Jom balik rumah.
The antidote is there.
Penawarnya ada.
I'm sorry.
saya minta maaf.
Don't cry.
jangan menangis.
I'm sorry, Leader.
Saya minta maaf, Pemimpin.
It's all right.
Tidak mengapa.
I don't blame you for that.
Saya tidak menyalahkan anda untuk itu.
Leader.
Pemimpin.
I'd like to have a word with General Li.
Saya ingin bercakap dengan Jeneral Li.
Thank you for saving my life then.
Terima kasih kerana menyelamatkan nyawa saya ketika itu.
I saved your life?
Saya menyelamatkan nyawa awak?
Looks like you don't remember it.
Nampaknya awak tidak mengingatinya.
Five years ago, my family and I almost got killed in jail.
Lima tahun lalu, saya dan keluarga saya hampir terbunuh di penjara.
It was you who saved me,
Engkaulah yang menyelamatkanku,
not Li Aotian.
bukan Li Aotian.
It was dark in there,
Di sana gelap,
so I couldn't see your face clearly.
jadi saya tidak dapat melihat wajah awak dengan jelas.
I only remember there was a man who took the blows for me.
Saya hanya ingat ada seorang lelaki yang mengambil pukulan untuk saya.
General.
Umum.
You got the two scars on your back
Anda mendapat dua parut di belakang anda
from having saved me.
daripada telah menyelamatkan saya.
After that, Li Aotian was looking for someone to work for him in jail.
Selepas itu, Li Aotian sedang mencari seseorang untuk bekerja untuknya di penjara.
I actually mistook him for my savior.
Saya sebenarnya menyangka dia sebagai penyelamat saya.
All these years, I've loved the wrong man
All these years, I've loved the wrong man
and committed those grave mistakes.
and committed those grave mistakes.
Now there's no turning back for me.
Now there's no turning back for me.
Erniang was right.
Erniang was right.
Fate plays tricks on us.
Fate plays tricks on us.
General.
Umum.
My life belongs to you.
My life belongs to you.
If you want it,
If you want it,
just take it.
just take it.
Since Xinrou has spared your life,
Since Xinrou has spared your life,
I will do the same.
I will do the same.
Leave now.
Leave now.
General.
Umum.
You've broken everyone's trust.
You've broken everyone's trust.
You're a sinner.
You're a sinner.
That's all the more reason to live.
That's all the more reason to live.
You shall repent and atone for your sins.
You shall repent and atone for your sins.
I never expected her to try to poison me to death.
I never expected her to try to poison me to death.
Take the decoction.
Take the decoction.
And I never thought
And I never thought
I'd get to witness my own funeral.
I'd get to witness my own funeral.
Luckily, I sealed your blood in time
Luckily, I sealed your blood in time
to stop the poison from spreading.
to stop the poison from spreading.
Otherwise, the funeral would've become a reality.
Otherwise, the funeral would've become a reality.
Antidote...
Antidote...
Where's the antidote?
Where's the antidote?
I'm sorry.
saya minta maaf.
I lied to you.
I lied to you.
Actually, there's no antidote to it.
Actually, there's no antidote to it.
Li Chengyu.
Li Chengyu.
Forgive me.
Forgive me.
I...
saya...
I just want to spend more time with you.
I just want to spend more time with you.
And...
And...
And I'd like to tell you a secret.
And I'd like to tell you a secret.
I'm actually from the modern world.
I'm actually from the modern world.
So are you.
So are you.
I know.
I know.
You knew it all along?
You knew it all along?
Since I was a kid,
Since I was a kid,
I always hoped a great hero in armor would appear,
I always hoped a great hero in armor would appear,
(charging into battle for me.)
(charging into battle for me.)
Until
Until
you showed up.
you showed up.
I'm not afraid of dying.
I'm not afraid of dying.
I'm just afraid
I'm just afraid
that once I die,
that once I die,
I'll never see you again.
I'll never see you again.
If I hadn't almost lost my life,
If I hadn't almost lost my life,
you still wouldn't have told me the truth.
you still wouldn't have told me the truth.
Li Aotian and the Chancellor are sworn enemies at court.
Li Aotian and the Chancellor are sworn enemies at court.
He's been recruiting troops and stockpiling arms for long.
He's been recruiting troops and stockpiling arms for long.
He even incited the Vice Minister of War to rebel.
He even incited the Vice Minister of War to rebel.
When that failed,
When that failed,
he tried to pin the blame on the Chancellor
he tried to pin the blame on the Chancellor
so as to get rid of his rivals.
so as to get rid of his rivals.
You were just one of his pawns.
You were just one of his pawns.
It just so happened
It just so happened
you became his excuse to frame the Chancellor.
you became his excuse to frame the Chancellor.
Manyue had always been loyal to Li Aotian.
Manyue had always been loyal to Li Aotian.
Both of us fell for the same poison.
Both of us fell for the same poison.
So that's how it is.
So that's how it is.
On the day of the palace coup,
On the day of the palace coup,
the real Li Chengyu was probably already poisoned to death.
the real Li Chengyu was probably already poisoned to death.
That's why I showed up.
That's why I showed up.
Speaking of which,
Speaking of which,
let me give you some good news.
let me give you some good news.
I know how to cure
I know how to cure
your poison now.
your poison now.
For real?
For real?
Mm.
Mm.
I knew nothing about its ingredients,
I knew nothing about its ingredients,
so I had no idea how to cure it.
so I had no idea how to cure it.
Having experienced it myself, I know the way now.
Having experienced it myself, I know the way now.
(Qingfeng Stronghold)
(Kubu kuat Qingfeng)
♪If you've never seen a bloom, you can't know hope♪
???Jika anda tidak pernah melihat bunga, anda tidak boleh tahu harapan???
♪If you weren't here, I wouldn't have come♪
???Kalau awak tak ada, saya takkan datang???
♪On a soda-lit night, only the wind knows my love♪
???Pada malam bercahaya soda, hanya angin yang tahu cintaku???
♪It's a helpless kind of feeling♪
???Perasaan macam tak berdaya???
♪Like a feather of morning love falling into the deep sea♪
???Seperti bulu cinta pagi yang jatuh ke laut dalam???
♪Being unnoticed, yet I still tell you I love you♪
???Sebab tanpa disedari, namun saya masih memberitahu awak saya sayang awak???
♪But my confession is drowned out by the wind♪
???Tetapi pengakuan saya ditenggelamkan oleh angin???
♪You can't hear it♪
???Anda tidak boleh mendengarnya???
♪I also want to rush forward♪
???Saya juga mahu tergesa-gesa ke hadapan???
♪To give you all my heart♪
???Untuk memberikan anda semua hati saya???
♪Yet it's pushed away by you♪
???Namun ia ditolak oleh anda???
♪Whether love is spoken or left unspoken♪
???Sama ada cinta terucap atau dibiarkan tak terucap???
♪I know you understand♪
???Saya tahu awak faham???
♪It's just an accident♪
???Ia hanya kemalangan???
♪You longed to wander once more, by my side through the throng♪
???Anda ingin merayau sekali lagi, di sisi saya melalui kerumunan???
♪I know you weren't really here for me♪
???Saya tahu awak bukan di sini untuk saya???
♪Yet still, who else could bring a surprise quite like you♪
???Namun, siapa lagi yang boleh membawa kejutan seperti anda???
♪After you left, I didn't want to let go♪
???Selepas awak pergi, saya tak nak lepaskan???
♪You brushed past me, leaving your trace in the crowd♪
???Anda menepis saya, meninggalkan jejak anda di khalayak ramai???
♪I didn't shut you out♪
???Saya tak tutup mulut awak???
♪But I couldn't wait for you to stop♪
???Tetapi saya tidak sabar untuk anda berhenti???
♪Yet I seem to clutch you, unable to let you fade into the crowd♪
???Namun saya seolah-olah mencengkam anda, tidak dapat membiarkan anda memudar di hadapan orang ramai???